<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Side Lower</title>
    <description>Random Ramblings of SB</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 12:30:02 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 12:30:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator><item>
        <title>Two Cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he following is a collection of photos of some of my experiences in Calcutta and Jamshedpur in the present year writing about whom has been held up owing to me getting involved in some other things. Some of the images brought back wistful memories of mine associated with these cities. Nothing special, completely ordinary, maybe mundane. But sometimes, someone’s monotonous experiences can be someone else’s aberrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calcutta&quot;&gt;Calcutta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/calcutta-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Howrah Bridge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old yet grand and iconic. In all my travels to the city, I have taken the train and arrived at I have always taken the train to come to Howrah. As I come out of the grand station, the first thing I do is turn towards the left and take a look at the thing which has come to represent the city ever since it was built. Grand. Impeccable. Unlike any other. The Howrah Bridge. This structure has become the motif of Calcutta and although there is a new bridge just down the south, it pales in comparison to the magnificence of the old. My earliest memory of this city has been the Howrah Bridge like countless others. It exudes a timeless appeal. Again, just like the city to which it connects. Calcutta always gives me the old-world charm. It seems to have made a cocoon for itself and stayed there in limbo, refusing to let go of the past, a habit which has earned the chagrin of many. The past was powerful, alluring, grand before the baton was passed to the new city to the north of India. While Mumbai has a Navi Mumbai and Delhi, a New Delhi, Calcutta doesn’t seem to have anything. It is making the change within itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Old Faithfuls outside Howrah Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calcutta is a city of unique contrasts and juxtapositions. The taxis are still the old yellow Ambassadors with a cranky suspension and almost always having a Bihari driver. Many streets still bear the name of its imperial masters. The Flurys, Mocambos and the Peter Cats still find its clientele amidst the Taj Bengals, Sonar Banglas and Novotels. This city feels old, grand, vibrant when one travels towards the innards of the city while taking in the history of the architectures while passing by the Esplanade Mansion, the now-empty Writer’s Building, through the vast expanse and greenery of the Maidan, and by the imposing Fort William. As I move further south, the journey becomes somewhat less pleasurable. Closely built, cheap houses, the haphazard network of small roads connecting to the main thoroughfare, high rising apartments coming up on any available parcel, the yet to be completed grey metro columns jutting out from the middle of the road, the dingy alleyways from where a fetid smell arises. I roll up the window of the taxi if it is still functional and check the time remaining to reach my destination. Calcutta may have become Kolkata but it has not yet attained a new self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This city has been a centre of intense politics for more than a century aided by the social Renaissance of Bengal in the mid-19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. What was once a beacon for the rest of India, slowly came to be despised. While the political overlords of Bengal have changed, some ideologies propagated over the 3 decades of rule by the Communists still remain. This is the only city perhaps apart from those in Kerala where the flags bearing the hammer and sickle can still be seen fluttering from the nondescript small tea stall or on a tree long after people have rejected them. Its colleges are still places of fierce debates and politics and it is here where the ideology thrives even though it has been accepted that the 3 decades of misrule demoted Bengal and brought one of the greatest cities to its shadows. But the rallies continue unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Book Fairs are more than just about books&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was present at the Kolkata Book Fair this year and here suddenly a crowd gathered, placards in hand, handmade posters were drawn and a rally began protesting against a new law by the Government of India. The people didn’t seem to mind, the administration didn’t care. What is interesting is that the crowd consisted of the young students with bags still from the colleges and the white-haired gents in kurtas and black sandals who seemed to relive their younger days when they would be out in the streets doing exactly the same thing. On one side the protest continued and on the other people were standing in a line to enter a bookshop inside the fair. De’s Publication has the best and most affordable books I was told. Two elderly men in the queue, their hands full of bags containing books rued the rise of paperbacks. “They don’t last long enough and still these publishers keep on bringing them.” Only in Calcutta. Tired from walking over 3 hours, resting under the shade of a tree, I was approached by a young girl, pointing towards the Penguin bag in my hand she asked where is that stall located. Only in Calcutta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Waiting Halls in Howrah&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making my way back to Jamshedpur, I was a few hours early at Howrah Station. Whenever I am at a waiting hall, I try to observe my fellow co-passengers. This is the week before the lock down. People are seen with masks. Some are snoring. Others listening to the announcements. A girl is spraying sanitizer on her palms before opening the pack of chips, another is talking on the phone quite audible to be heard. She missed the connecting local. The next one is 2 hours later. The dejection could be felt in her voice. A father beside me, instructing his daughter to buy an India Today and an Ananda Bazaar Patrika at the Wheeler shop. A group huddling together near the switchboard to charge their mobiles, the devices resting in a precarious position on the edge. A call came, the device vibrated, its owner a little late in reaching. The phones tumbled down. An altercation ensued. I find the waiting room much fascinating. A station like Howrah ensures that there is never a dull moment when you are waiting. You sit, you observe and you become an audience in this theatre, while you yourself are someone else’s actor unknowingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jamshedpur&quot;&gt;Jamshedpur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am brought up in Jamshedpur. It’s a city which I come to love and chide with equal measure. There was a time, when I wanted to escape from this place, go somewhere far, unreachable and chart a new self. Someplace where I could be different than what the city tried to make me. Jamshedpur suffers from a lack of imagination and thoughts. The voices heralding something different are few and they too become quiet over the years as they assimilate within its folds. There is a heterogeneous culture in this city but its thoughts have been that of a homogeneous variety. A town established with workers working in a steel factory which was managed by the Europeans and Americans could never develop a culture of its own. This city chases success. The dearth of a culture of its own and the inability to forge its own identity outside the factories lead to a myopic view of success only in the fields of engineering and exams. After all, why not? The entire city was built around the proficiency of engineers and the industries. This is a place where a VP of Tata Steel or Tata Motors has more influence and is much revered than the local councillor. All the R Madhavans and Imtiaz Alis found their success when they left. This is a place where examination toppers sit between their parents flashing a smile while their interviews are taken. If one is an aberration, there is chaos. At one time, I wasn’t doing too well and that naturally led to an uncomfortable disquiet in my home. I wanted to run away cause this place was difficult. On an early February morning, as I was standing outside in the sun, I happened to notice the shadows made by the gate with its intersections of wire. I kept looking at it. Past memories surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seldom realize the importance of a person, a place or a thing until it is taken away from us. Years later after I have travelled the past most chosen on my own volition, I have come to realize the importance of experiences and skills which this city taught me. Now I cherish my association with this city which moulded me as I grew up. From hatred, a love, a desire grew. This place is not perfect just like everything else but this is home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one has seen Udaan, then one can recall this place. The ending scene, Rohan and his brother Arjun holding hands as they walk through a shaded pathway to a new life with hope and a smile. The past year mostly the latter half was a testing time for me. Sleep was hard to come by and always laced with worry. While the outer self, portrayed a perfectly fine, laughing person, going on my daily routine, the inside me was crumbling. It was difficult to explain to someone. What do you do when you are questioning yourself every moment? During these times, I found my comfort in the lyrics of the songs from Udaan. Naav being my favourite. I have this habit of making a timetable for my class since the second year of college and then adding a little line one or two just for some bad days or for fun. My last semester had the lines –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
‘Hai Dil Mei Roshni Tere Tu Cheer Daal Sab Ghere &lt;br /&gt;
Lehron Ki Gardan Kas Ke Daal Fandey Re &lt;br /&gt;
Ki Dariyan Bole Waaha Re Panthi &lt;br /&gt;
Sar Ankhon Pe Naav Hai Teri Naav Hai Teri’
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was way before my bad times since I had a premonition about something bad to happen. A cynic. Standing on the spot a winter afternoon this year, I amused at how everything tied together. The city I wanted to run from gave me strength when I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that know me, might know how much I have been into letters and postcards the past year. There is never a greater sense of joy than receiving a handwritten postcard in your mailbox. Someone took the effort and love to send you a greeting or piece of their life. It is slow sometimes it is never delivered yet; I can vouch that it is much beautiful and truer in feelings than a WhatsApp greeting. This February, I started again after a pause of sending a few postcards. Got some special stamps, filling a new ink pen and writing away. The happiness I derive from this task is second to my love for railways perhaps. Over the months I have received many postcards and a few letters and always this has drawn the curiosities of others who sometimes laugh away or are amazed. Different people, different choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he following is a collection of photos of some of my experiences in Calcutta and Jamshedpur in the present year writing about whom has been held up owing to me getting involved in some other things. Some of the images brought back wistful memories of mine associated with these cities. Nothing special, completely ordinary, maybe mundane. But sometimes, someone’s monotonous experiences can be someone else’s aberrant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/28/two-cities</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/28/two-cities</guid></item><item>
        <title>The Intercity to Delhi</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;t 7 in the morning in late October, when Patiala was still sleeping, enveloped in the early morning fog, the few people outside could be seen with shawls trying to beat the mild chill of the Northern Plains, when the streets were still quiet and the harmonious surroundings were not yet invaded by the diesel autos, the few strays still too sleepy to register irritation at the person who trespassed into their territory, Patiala Railway Station was a sharp departure from the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 7:33 Intercity to Delhi would arrive soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance Patiala could be easily mistaken for just another small-town railway station – there is no outwardly visible clues to its history or its design. The station serving the capital of the PEPSU region is built perpendicular to the rail line. The platform 1 with its arched steel and tin covering, its pillar designed with circular support is vastly different from other stations of India. The Maharaja had grand plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Patiala&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thapar people rarely take the train to Delhi, preferring the much more comfortable and faster service by the Volvo and Scania buses. Just before vacations, a few of them can be spotted near the place marked for the Chair Car coach, perhaps unable to secure a ticket home due to the rush. A few unfortunate ones whose decision was made on a short notice, thereby missing out on the comforts of the air-conditioned sanctuary but having enough time to book a ticket, gaze into the distance near the front of the station marked for the few reserved coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival of the train was marked by quick and harried activity. The train stops for 2 minutes and today it stopped way before its marked point, making people to run for with luggage on hand and children on other. This bond between the older matured hand and the small tender hand was held tightly. The matured hand has seen much of the world than to allow it to hold the hand lightly. Breaking into a run, I too joined their ranks. My hands instead carrying a bag, the weight of which I believe was mimic my own – the result of a long overdue visit home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Early mornings at Patiala&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, I paused to catch my breath. The carriage was moderately empty. I found my window seat, put my bag underneath the seat, my bag pack tucked away safely at the top, sat down and massaged my sore shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the blare of the horn, the train started, I looked outside. The platform now deprived of its temporary inhabitants which made it come alive, now went back its unhurried and insipid existence until the arrival of the next train. The lone vendor on the platform was putting back his freshly made pakodas into different compartments of his stall – waiting for the next train to bring passengers. This is all like a clockwork – the stopping of the few passenger trains, opening of the gates, exchange of token – repetitive and monotonous. There is hardly anything exciting happening on the station. Yet, Patiala has its charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brilliant beams of the golden sun gave a splendid shade to the Punjab countryside. At the distance, the yellow fields merged with the slanting rays as if part of a single entity. A low-lying mist overhangs the fields giving the entire setting a hazy, mysterious appearance. The light is welcomed in all quarters in equal measure. Its warmth embraced gleefully in the mild chilly weather. Inside the compartment the fresh and cool crispy air coming in through the open windows made a few wrap their jackets and shawls closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The compartment was an old one where two rows of seats face each other as if to facilitate conversations. In 2019, it didn’t. A middle-aged man, balding, small in height with a bandage on his leg and a tiny voice occupied the window seat. From time to time, he kept adjusting his leg to make it a little more comfortable on the hard-cushioned seat. His view was fixed outside, as if thinking about some problem. The trance broken by the calls where he kept mentioning someone his coach number. To my right was well built, lean and tall man. Wearing a red jacket and khaki coloured pants, his grave face made me think him of a police officer on leave. My imagination was given backing when he asked the young man on his opposite to down the glass shutter. ‘It’s cold inside.’ His voice boomed. More like an order than a request. The young man complied after taking some time to register the fact that a protest would be futile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Intercity to Delhi travels from the border town of Fazilka to the quarters of Old Delhi, passing through towns which seldom heard of in the context of Punjab. Small towns lying on single track, through which development comes in slowly – often leftovers of the big cities of Jalandhar, Ludhiana and Amritsar. The slow march of development did not hamper the growth of technology among the residents of such towns. In the compartment, most of them were busy on their phones and watching some YouTube video on the moving train. This last bit heralded by the affordable Internet plans – a sight unheard barely 5 years ago. The conversations were negligent. People were trying to catch some sleep broken by their early morning trip to the station, their heads bobbing with the motion of the coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small girl of about 5 or 6 years held the dupatta of her mother’s salwar as she gave the most sweetest smile and tried to sing some Hindi song as she waited for the train to stop at Ambala. Her mother irritated by her younger brother on her shoulder who was constantly trying to break into wail, didn’t pay much attention to her. The father, looking lovingly at his daughter said, ‘Kya hua beta? Bohot pareshan kar rahi hai’ Definitely not meaning the last words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival at Ambala Cantt saw most of the carriage emptying. The seats quickly taken up by the newcomers without a reserved ticket. The window seat was vacated by the small man and I quickly moved to the most cherished place on a train, lest it be taken by someone. Smells of bread omelette, aloo puri, break pakoda wafted in through the windows. I felt hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vacant space beside me was taken up by a man in his 50’s wearing a striped blue shirt, deep blue pants and large shell frame glasses. He was carrying a black office going bag. As soon as he sat down, he took out his phone and seldom looked away from it until the TTE asked for his ticket. He kept himself busy texting people on WhatsApp and spent a lot of time to reply to one of his many forwards with the best emoji. In the end he settled for the time and tested one of folded hands and a smiling face. Experimentation can wait.  Kept checking back for more replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ambala also brought with it the much needed TTE. The sight of him made many stand up and travel to the end coaches. In such trains, the distinction between the general and reserved coaches are seldom made. One of the young man opposite to me, promptly took a call and pretended to talk while moving away to the door. When the TTE left, he came back. His seat was being kept by his bag. The middle-aged woman from Rajpura travelling alone spoke before giving the TTE a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Mere brother Kulvir Singh railway staff hai. Shatabdi mein jaate. Ticket bana do.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Thik hai, thik bana dunga.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Waise mai bhi staff hu.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The necessary transaction thus completed and uncertainty settled, she went back to her slumbering state. The infelicitous ones kept looking at her with a scorn as they made their way back. Argument was useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Life on tracks at Ambala Cantt Jn&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside, the country side changed. From single storied houses without plaster to painted ones and sometimes even having a double story as a major town approach. The approach and the departure from Ambala were marked by such two storied houses, often with a saffron flag lifted on a pole. There was mostly a temple nearby. Sometimes, these houses had the flag of the BJP fluttering, it being barely discernible from the temple ones. The flag of the opposition was nonexistent. Election season has just ended in Haryana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the small-town station, where the train did not stop quainter and cleaner. There was no one except the lone guard who lifted the green flag for the passing train. The stations had the luxury of having flowering plants in comparison to its bigger counterparts. Most often having bougainvillea plants in their pink and yellow in full bloom, overflowing their guarded enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tracks led towards Delhi, the view outside the window acquired an anaemic look. Houses turned increasingly ugly, built on any available land without any thought. Even the fields were layered with hazy fog, refusing to move. The streams passing underneath changed colours from a bluish to a darker shade of green, having an obnoxious stench. The tracks became dusty and a fine layer of dust covered the passengers when an opposite train passed. The view looked heavy, strenuous. I took to sleep at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panipat saw a deluge of bread pakoda sellers. Bread kha lo. Garam bread le lo. Haanji, garam bread pakode. They arrived in a wave. For a stoppage of only 2 minutes, each tried to convince us to buy their cold, greasy, bland and often unhygienic bread pakoda using their cries as their unique selling points. The one with the most different call, got the most customers. 2 minutes the train stopped and many pakodas were sold. The vision of our PM seems to find its voice in Panipat station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Delhi Circular Railway is now mostly a remnant of the past. The stations now empty, people not passengers sitting and staring blankly into the distance, talking. Some smoke cigarettes. They know they won’t be caught. There is no one else. Sometime, the odd local comes, but there are few takers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two storied houses gave way to tall, modern buildings. The garbage increased. Cows, people, pigs all scavenging in the same place. At some point, plastic was being burnt. The stench became unbearable. Yet people lived in such squalor, in small, cramped dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Rush hour at Subzi Mandi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People left at Subzi Mandi. In a daring show of bravery, they jumped onto the tracks to climb on to platform 1 before a train comes. A train did come. The locomotive blaring the horn nonstop which can make even the deaf hear. There is a hope and a prayer in this. Hope that no one comes in between and today no one did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Subzi Mandi, the pace slowed down to a crawl. Tall, grey buildings guarded the blackened tracks. Someone got pushed by the luggage near the door. An angry expletive registered the disapproval of the action. Delhi has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Old Delhi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;t 7 in the morning in late October, when Patiala was still sleeping, enveloped in the early morning fog, the few people outside could be seen with shawls trying to beat the mild chill of the Northern Plains, when the streets were still quiet and the harmonious surroundings were not yet invaded by the diesel autos, the few strays still too sleepy to register irritation at the person who trespassed into their territory, Patiala Railway Station was a sharp departure from the above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/26/intercity-to-delhi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/26/intercity-to-delhi</guid></item><item>
        <title>Example Post Formatting</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heading-1&quot;&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-2&quot;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heading-3&quot;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heading-4&quot;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading-5&quot;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading-6&quot;&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Donec sed odio dui. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unordered-list&quot;&gt;Unordered List&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longer List Item
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested List Item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ordered-list&quot;&gt;Ordered List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longer List Item
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested OL Item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;definition-list&quot;&gt;Definition List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Coffee&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Black hot drink&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Milk&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;White cold drink&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Donec sed odio dui. Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/15/example-post-formatting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/15/example-post-formatting</guid></item><item>
        <title>Featured Image</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/14/featured-image</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/14/featured-image</guid></item><item>
        <title>Post With A Code Snippet</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt;ou'll find this post in your `_posts` directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the `-w` switch) to see your changes! To add new posts, simply add a file in the `_posts` directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt;ou'll find this post in your `_posts` directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the `-w` switch) to see your changes! To add new posts, simply add a file in the `_posts` directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/13/code-snippet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/13/code-snippet</guid></item><item>
        <title>Figure With A Caption</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/touring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fig1. - This is an example figcaption&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/assets/img/touring.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Fig1. - This is an example figcaption&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/12/figure-with-caption</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/12/figure-with-caption</guid></item><item>
        <title>Image in Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/touring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/11/image-in-post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/11/image-in-post</guid></item><item>
        <title>Test Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/10/test-post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/10/test-post</guid></item></channel>
</rss>
