<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Side Lower</title>
    <description>Random Ramblings of SB</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:41:20 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:41:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator><item>
        <title>Two Cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he following is a collection of photos of some of my experiences in Calcutta and Jamshedpur in the present year writing about whom has been held up owing to me getting involved in some other things. Some of the images brought back wistful memories of mine associated with these cities. Nothing special, completely ordinary, maybe mundane. But sometimes, someone’s monotonous experiences can be someone else’s aberrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calcutta&quot;&gt;Calcutta&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/calcutta-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Howrah Bridge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old yet grand and iconic. In all my travels to the city, I have taken the train and arrived at I have always taken the train to come to Howrah. As I come out of the grand station, the first thing I do is turn towards the left and take a look at the thing which has come to represent the city ever since it was built. Grand. Impeccable. Unlike any other. The Howrah Bridge. This structure has become the motif of Calcutta and although there is a new bridge just down the south, it pales in comparison to the magnificence of the old. My earliest memory of this city has been the Howrah Bridge like countless others. It exudes a timeless appeal. Again, just like the city to which it connects. Calcutta always gives me the old-world charm. It seems to have made a cocoon for itself and stayed there in limbo, refusing to let go of the past, a habit which has earned the chagrin of many. The past was powerful, alluring, grand before the baton was passed to the new city to the north of India. While Mumbai has a Navi Mumbai and Delhi, a New Delhi, Calcutta doesn’t seem to have anything. It is making the change within itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Old Faithfuls outside Howrah Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calcutta is a city of unique contrasts and juxtapositions. The taxis are still the old yellow Ambassadors with a cranky suspension and almost always having a Bihari driver. Many streets still bear the name of its imperial masters. The Flurys, Mocambos and the Peter Cats still find its clientele amidst the Taj Bengals, Sonar Banglas and Novotels. This city feels old, grand, vibrant when one travels towards the innards of the city while taking in the history of the architectures while passing by the Esplanade Mansion, the now-empty Writer’s Building, through the vast expanse and greenery of the Maidan, and by the imposing Fort William. As I move further south, the journey becomes somewhat less pleasurable. Closely built, cheap houses, the haphazard network of small roads connecting to the main thoroughfare, high rising apartments coming up on any available parcel, the yet to be completed grey metro columns jutting out from the middle of the road, the dingy alleyways from where a fetid smell arises. I roll up the window of the taxi if it is still functional and check the time remaining to reach my destination. Calcutta may have become Kolkata but it has not yet attained a new self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This city has been a centre of intense politics for more than a century aided by the social Renaissance of Bengal in the mid-19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. What was once a beacon for the rest of India, slowly came to be despised. While the political overlords of Bengal have changed, some ideologies propagated over the 3 decades of rule by the Communists still remain. This is the only city perhaps apart from those in Kerala where the flags bearing the hammer and sickle can still be seen fluttering from the nondescript small tea stall or on a tree long after people have rejected them. Its colleges are still places of fierce debates and politics and it is here where the ideology thrives even though it has been accepted that the 3 decades of misrule demoted Bengal and brought one of the greatest cities to its shadows. But the rallies continue unfazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Book Fairs are more than just about books&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was present at the Kolkata Book Fair this year and here suddenly a crowd gathered, placards in hand, handmade posters were drawn and a rally began protesting against a new law by the Government of India. The people didn’t seem to mind, the administration didn’t care. What is interesting is that the crowd consisted of the young students with bags still from the colleges and the white-haired gents in kurtas and black sandals who seemed to relive their younger days when they would be out in the streets doing exactly the same thing. On one side the protest continued and on the other people were standing in a line to enter a bookshop inside the fair. De’s Publication has the best and most affordable books I was told. Two elderly men in the queue, their hands full of bags containing books rued the rise of paperbacks. “They don’t last long enough and still these publishers keep on bringing them.” Only in Calcutta. Tired from walking over 3 hours, resting under the shade of a tree, I was approached by a young girl, pointing towards the Penguin bag in my hand she asked where is that stall located. Only in Calcutta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Waiting Halls in Howrah&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making my way back to Jamshedpur, I was a few hours early at Howrah Station. Whenever I am at a waiting hall, I try to observe my fellow co-passengers. This is the week before the lock down. People are seen with masks. Some are snoring. Others listening to the announcements. A girl is spraying sanitizer on her palms before opening the pack of chips, another is talking on the phone quite audible to be heard. She missed the connecting local. The next one is 2 hours later. The dejection could be felt in her voice. A father beside me, instructing his daughter to buy an India Today and an Ananda Bazaar Patrika at the Wheeler shop. A group huddling together near the switchboard to charge their mobiles, the devices resting in a precarious position on the edge. A call came, the device vibrated, its owner a little late in reaching. The phones tumbled down. An altercation ensued. I find the waiting room much fascinating. A station like Howrah ensures that there is never a dull moment when you are waiting. You sit, you observe and you become an audience in this theatre, while you yourself are someone else’s actor unknowingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jamshedpur&quot;&gt;Jamshedpur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am brought up in Jamshedpur. It’s a city which I come to love and chide with equal measure. There was a time, when I wanted to escape from this place, go somewhere far, unreachable and chart a new self. Someplace where I could be different than what the city tried to make me. Jamshedpur suffers from a lack of imagination and thoughts. The voices heralding something different are few and they too become quiet over the years as they assimilate within its folds. There is a heterogeneous culture in this city but its thoughts have been that of a homogeneous variety. A town established with workers working in a steel factory which was managed by the Europeans and Americans could never develop a culture of its own. This city chases success. The dearth of a culture of its own and the inability to forge its own identity outside the factories lead to a myopic view of success only in the fields of engineering and exams. After all, why not? The entire city was built around the proficiency of engineers and the industries. This is a place where a VP of Tata Steel or Tata Motors has more influence and is much revered than the local councillor. All the R Madhavans and Imtiaz Alis found their success when they left. This is a place where examination toppers sit between their parents flashing a smile while their interviews are taken. If one is an aberration, there is chaos. At one time, I wasn’t doing too well and that naturally led to an uncomfortable disquiet in my home. I wanted to run away cause this place was difficult. On an early February morning, as I was standing outside in the sun, I happened to notice the shadows made by the gate with its intersections of wire. I kept looking at it. Past memories surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seldom realize the importance of a person, a place or a thing until it is taken away from us. Years later after I have travelled the past most chosen on my own volition, I have come to realize the importance of experiences and skills which this city taught me. Now I cherish my association with this city which moulded me as I grew up. From hatred, a love, a desire grew. This place is not perfect just like everything else but this is home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one has seen Udaan, then one can recall this place. The ending scene, Rohan and his brother Arjun holding hands as they walk through a shaded pathway to a new life with hope and a smile. The past year mostly the latter half was a testing time for me. Sleep was hard to come by and always laced with worry. While the outer self, portrayed a perfectly fine, laughing person, going on my daily routine, the inside me was crumbling. It was difficult to explain to someone. What do you do when you are questioning yourself every moment? During these times, I found my comfort in the lyrics of the songs from Udaan. Naav being my favourite. I have this habit of making a timetable for my class since the second year of college and then adding a little line one or two just for some bad days or for fun. My last semester had the lines –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
‘Hai Dil Mei Roshni Tere Tu Cheer Daal Sab Ghere &lt;br /&gt;
Lehron Ki Gardan Kas Ke Daal Fandey Re &lt;br /&gt;
Ki Dariyan Bole Waaha Re Panthi &lt;br /&gt;
Sar Ankhon Pe Naav Hai Teri Naav Hai Teri’
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was way before my bad times since I had a premonition about something bad to happen. A cynic. Standing on the spot a winter afternoon this year, I amused at how everything tied together. The city I wanted to run from gave me strength when I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that know me, might know how much I have been into letters and postcards the past year. There is never a greater sense of joy than receiving a handwritten postcard in your mailbox. Someone took the effort and love to send you a greeting or piece of their life. It is slow sometimes it is never delivered yet; I can vouch that it is much beautiful and truer in feelings than a WhatsApp greeting. This February, I started again after a pause of sending a few postcards. Got some special stamps, filling a new ink pen and writing away. The happiness I derive from this task is second to my love for railways perhaps. Over the months I have received many postcards and a few letters and always this has drawn the curiosities of others who sometimes laugh away or are amazed. Different people, different choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/two-cities-9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he following is a collection of photos of some of my experiences in Calcutta and Jamshedpur in the present year writing about whom has been held up owing to me getting involved in some other things. Some of the images brought back wistful memories of mine associated with these cities. Nothing special, completely ordinary, maybe mundane. But sometimes, someone’s monotonous experiences can be someone else’s aberrant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/28/two-cities</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/28/two-cities</guid></item><item>
        <title>The Intercity to Delhi</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;t 7 in the morning in late October, when Patiala was still sleeping, enveloped in the early morning fog, the few people outside could be seen with shawls trying to beat the mild chill of the Northern Plains, when the streets were still quiet and the harmonious surroundings were not yet invaded by the diesel autos, the few strays still too sleepy to register irritation at the person who trespassed into their territory, Patiala Railway Station was a sharp departure from the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 7:33 Intercity to Delhi would arrive soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance Patiala could be easily mistaken for just another small-town railway station – there is no outwardly visible clues to its history or its design. The station serving the capital of the PEPSU region is built perpendicular to the rail line. The platform 1 with its arched steel and tin covering, its pillar designed with circular support is vastly different from other stations of India. The Maharaja had grand plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Patiala&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thapar people rarely take the train to Delhi, preferring the much more comfortable and faster service by the Volvo and Scania buses. Just before vacations, a few of them can be spotted near the place marked for the Chair Car coach, perhaps unable to secure a ticket home due to the rush. A few unfortunate ones whose decision was made on a short notice, thereby missing out on the comforts of the air-conditioned sanctuary but having enough time to book a ticket, gaze into the distance near the front of the station marked for the few reserved coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival of the train was marked by quick and harried activity. The train stops for 2 minutes and today it stopped way before its marked point, making people to run for with luggage on hand and children on other. This bond between the older matured hand and the small tender hand was held tightly. The matured hand has seen much of the world than to allow it to hold the hand lightly. Breaking into a run, I too joined their ranks. My hands instead carrying a bag, the weight of which I believe was mimic my own – the result of a long overdue visit home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Early mornings at Patiala&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, I paused to catch my breath. The carriage was moderately empty. I found my window seat, put my bag underneath the seat, my bag pack tucked away safely at the top, sat down and massaged my sore shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the blare of the horn, the train started, I looked outside. The platform now deprived of its temporary inhabitants which made it come alive, now went back its unhurried and insipid existence until the arrival of the next train. The lone vendor on the platform was putting back his freshly made pakodas into different compartments of his stall – waiting for the next train to bring passengers. This is all like a clockwork – the stopping of the few passenger trains, opening of the gates, exchange of token – repetitive and monotonous. There is hardly anything exciting happening on the station. Yet, Patiala has its charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brilliant beams of the golden sun gave a splendid shade to the Punjab countryside. At the distance, the yellow fields merged with the slanting rays as if part of a single entity. A low-lying mist overhangs the fields giving the entire setting a hazy, mysterious appearance. The light is welcomed in all quarters in equal measure. Its warmth embraced gleefully in the mild chilly weather. Inside the compartment the fresh and cool crispy air coming in through the open windows made a few wrap their jackets and shawls closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The compartment was an old one where two rows of seats face each other as if to facilitate conversations. In 2019, it didn’t. A middle-aged man, balding, small in height with a bandage on his leg and a tiny voice occupied the window seat. From time to time, he kept adjusting his leg to make it a little more comfortable on the hard-cushioned seat. His view was fixed outside, as if thinking about some problem. The trance broken by the calls where he kept mentioning someone his coach number. To my right was well built, lean and tall man. Wearing a red jacket and khaki coloured pants, his grave face made me think him of a police officer on leave. My imagination was given backing when he asked the young man on his opposite to down the glass shutter. ‘It’s cold inside.’ His voice boomed. More like an order than a request. The young man complied after taking some time to register the fact that a protest would be futile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Intercity to Delhi travels from the border town of Fazilka to the quarters of Old Delhi, passing through towns which seldom heard of in the context of Punjab. Small towns lying on single track, through which development comes in slowly – often leftovers of the big cities of Jalandhar, Ludhiana and Amritsar. The slow march of development did not hamper the growth of technology among the residents of such towns. In the compartment, most of them were busy on their phones and watching some YouTube video on the moving train. This last bit heralded by the affordable Internet plans – a sight unheard barely 5 years ago. The conversations were negligent. People were trying to catch some sleep broken by their early morning trip to the station, their heads bobbing with the motion of the coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small girl of about 5 or 6 years held the dupatta of her mother’s salwar as she gave the most sweetest smile and tried to sing some Hindi song as she waited for the train to stop at Ambala. Her mother irritated by her younger brother on her shoulder who was constantly trying to break into wail, didn’t pay much attention to her. The father, looking lovingly at his daughter said, ‘Kya hua beta? Bohot pareshan kar rahi hai’ Definitely not meaning the last words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival at Ambala Cantt saw most of the carriage emptying. The seats quickly taken up by the newcomers without a reserved ticket. The window seat was vacated by the small man and I quickly moved to the most cherished place on a train, lest it be taken by someone. Smells of bread omelette, aloo puri, break pakoda wafted in through the windows. I felt hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vacant space beside me was taken up by a man in his 50’s wearing a striped blue shirt, deep blue pants and large shell frame glasses. He was carrying a black office going bag. As soon as he sat down, he took out his phone and seldom looked away from it until the TTE asked for his ticket. He kept himself busy texting people on WhatsApp and spent a lot of time to reply to one of his many forwards with the best emoji. In the end he settled for the time and tested one of folded hands and a smiling face. Experimentation can wait.  Kept checking back for more replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ambala also brought with it the much needed TTE. The sight of him made many stand up and travel to the end coaches. In such trains, the distinction between the general and reserved coaches are seldom made. One of the young man opposite to me, promptly took a call and pretended to talk while moving away to the door. When the TTE left, he came back. His seat was being kept by his bag. The middle-aged woman from Rajpura travelling alone spoke before giving the TTE a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Mere brother Kulvir Singh railway staff hai. Shatabdi mein jaate. Ticket bana do.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Thik hai, thik bana dunga.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Waise mai bhi staff hu.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The necessary transaction thus completed and uncertainty settled, she went back to her slumbering state. The infelicitous ones kept looking at her with a scorn as they made their way back. Argument was useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Life on tracks at Ambala Cantt Jn&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside, the country side changed. From single storied houses without plaster to painted ones and sometimes even having a double story as a major town approach. The approach and the departure from Ambala were marked by such two storied houses, often with a saffron flag lifted on a pole. There was mostly a temple nearby. Sometimes, these houses had the flag of the BJP fluttering, it being barely discernible from the temple ones. The flag of the opposition was nonexistent. Election season has just ended in Haryana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the small-town station, where the train did not stop quainter and cleaner. There was no one except the lone guard who lifted the green flag for the passing train. The stations had the luxury of having flowering plants in comparison to its bigger counterparts. Most often having bougainvillea plants in their pink and yellow in full bloom, overflowing their guarded enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the tracks led towards Delhi, the view outside the window acquired an anaemic look. Houses turned increasingly ugly, built on any available land without any thought. Even the fields were layered with hazy fog, refusing to move. The streams passing underneath changed colours from a bluish to a darker shade of green, having an obnoxious stench. The tracks became dusty and a fine layer of dust covered the passengers when an opposite train passed. The view looked heavy, strenuous. I took to sleep at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panipat saw a deluge of bread pakoda sellers. Bread kha lo. Garam bread le lo. Haanji, garam bread pakode. They arrived in a wave. For a stoppage of only 2 minutes, each tried to convince us to buy their cold, greasy, bland and often unhygienic bread pakoda using their cries as their unique selling points. The one with the most different call, got the most customers. 2 minutes the train stopped and many pakodas were sold. The vision of our PM seems to find its voice in Panipat station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Delhi Circular Railway is now mostly a remnant of the past. The stations now empty, people not passengers sitting and staring blankly into the distance, talking. Some smoke cigarettes. They know they won’t be caught. There is no one else. Sometime, the odd local comes, but there are few takers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two storied houses gave way to tall, modern buildings. The garbage increased. Cows, people, pigs all scavenging in the same place. At some point, plastic was being burnt. The stench became unbearable. Yet people lived in such squalor, in small, cramped dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Rush hour at Subzi Mandi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People left at Subzi Mandi. In a daring show of bravery, they jumped onto the tracks to climb on to platform 1 before a train comes. A train did come. The locomotive blaring the horn nonstop which can make even the deaf hear. There is a hope and a prayer in this. Hope that no one comes in between and today no one did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Subzi Mandi, the pace slowed down to a crawl. Tall, grey buildings guarded the blackened tracks. Someone got pushed by the luggage near the door. An angry expletive registered the disapproval of the action. Delhi has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/intercity-to-delhi-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Old Delhi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;t 7 in the morning in late October, when Patiala was still sleeping, enveloped in the early morning fog, the few people outside could be seen with shawls trying to beat the mild chill of the Northern Plains, when the streets were still quiet and the harmonious surroundings were not yet invaded by the diesel autos, the few strays still too sleepy to register irritation at the person who trespassed into their territory, Patiala Railway Station was a sharp departure from the above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/26/intercity-to-delhi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/26/intercity-to-delhi</guid></item><item>
        <title>Easy Like A Sunday Morning</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he past few weeks were different. Unexpected. But this article below, took me on a whirlwind tour back to my childhood looking through hazy, nostalgic glimpses of my memory. Thursdays meant TeleKids an TeleKids meant Feluda illustrated. I already feel like old typing this. Diminishing earnings from subscriptions has led Telegraph to alter its weekly supplicants, the new ones often a shadow in comparison to its earlier self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/easy-like-a-sunday-morning-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Feluda in The Hindu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But TeleKids was special. I learnt, laughed and explored through its coloured pages and Derek’s questions. This charminar smoking, dhoti clad Bengali bhadralok was introduced to me by my mother. Ray’s creation has amused and entertained two generations of the Bengali populace. For, my mother, Feluda is Soumitro Chatterjee and for her son, it is Sabyasachi Chakraborty. Watching one of your beloved character, brought to life by these greats is always thing to be treasured. I still remember vividly that when Gorosthaney Shabdhan (Beware at the Cemetery) was released in 2008, how impatient I was for it to come on TV (there were no cinema theaters showing Bengali films back then in Jamshedpur). When it did, almost 3 months later, how my entire family was engrossed. Jatayu’s seemingly innocent queries, Topshe’s eagerness to help his uncle to solve the mystery and ever suave, polished, all-knowing, a baritone to swoon by Pradosh C. Mitter, our very own Feluda is a treat to look out for. Feluda is almost everyone’s childhood hero. While other’s had Superman, Batman, I had Feluda. That character is something different in entirety! A voracious reader, a travel buff, sharp intellect and wit and a martial art aficionado (the first two points could have been done away with as being quintessential urban Bengali traits) . He is our very own Sherlock Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/21/Feluda_and_Topshe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother always rues the fact that I cannot read Bengali. ‘The stories are much more lively when read in Bengali’ she says. More than a decade later, I am still not proficient enough to feel confident to delve into the actual stories written by Ray. Have to do with the English translations though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotions this article evoked is a welcome break from all my negativity I have been having for the past few days. After all this is over, perhaps I will find my book again and relish those stories someday soon. I am yet to meet Byomkesh Bakshi or Kakababu, the two other detectives in the Bengali literature verse. May be they are as interesting as Feluda. But Feluda, for me will always keep reminding me of some good ol’ simple days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/movies/long-live-feluda-and-his-avatars-the-detectives-of-bengali-cinema/article29350937.ece&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he past few weeks were different. Unexpected. But this article below, took me on a whirlwind tour back to my childhood looking through hazy, nostalgic glimpses of my memory. Thursdays meant TeleKids an TeleKids meant Feluda illustrated. I already feel like old typing this. Diminishing earnings from subscriptions has led Telegraph to alter its weekly supplicants, the new ones often a shadow in comparison to its earlier self.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/08/easy-like-a-sunday-morning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/08/easy-like-a-sunday-morning</guid></item><item>
        <title>Why?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; have been asking this question to myself for the past one and a half hours. Particularly, Why Me? Why did I not get selected? A volley of emotions is raging through me right now. I feel dejected, hopeless, worthless, stupid. For the first time in months, I broke down.  I am questioning my feelings, my worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with rejection. I have been rejected before but none of them hurt as bad or is as painful as this one. The one on 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; August, 2019. It was my dream. The only one for which I have been waiting for. Just like the others. The past few days were strenuous. Running around giving tests, seeing the shortlists and the final results with double-digit LPA CTC with your name featuring nowhere and getting rejected is a difficult process. Emotionally. At least for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought my test went well. I cruised through the sections. Was confident of featuring in the shortlist. Just like the others. But, today, I didn’t. I saw the names of my friends up there but not mine. With every scroll in the Excel sheet, my heart was pounding not wanting to confront the fear which I harbour every time in such situations. I am a pessimist and have no qualms about that. The list reached its end at 194. My name is not there. Checked again. And again, and again. Reality does not change just because you want it to change. Right now, before my eyes, I saw my dream shatter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I have cried this much since schooldays. Every second is like a shard of glass piercing my heart, draining me. I am shattered. I am right now questioning my capabilities. Maybe I am not worth this entire process. I am mediocre. Mediocrity doesn’t last long. The glass palace built around some brief moments of brilliance crumbles down. I am such a structure and I am crumbling down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can I possibly talk to people now? Tell them that I am getting rejected in making to a list in which almost any well-rounded person makes the cut? I am ashamed of myself. I pity, loathe and detest my own existence. Some may question this is premature, childish and that there is a time for everyone. But, for people like me, when the time arrives, it’s too late. I have faced such situations every time something big comes up in my life – my college, or my biggest win till date and now this. To be honest, I am tired of feeding on the leftovers. I have lost all motivation now to do anything. My mind is bursting from my dead hopes and eyes are watery from confronting the reality. 2 hours have passed and still, I am not able to calm myself down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching people, friends get placed is a good feeling but realizing that you are not among them, kills. My door has been knocked more than 10 times since the result was announced. Didn’t open. Why? During this point, people have enough sympathy to give. What more is there to share? What words can soothe the mediocre existence of a person? None. But I don’t want any of it. Because I am done. Now, I just want to be left alone. I want to cry alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I deleted my WhatsApp because I don’t want to see it anymore. There is nothing worth in for me. I know, I will get more and more cynical, cranky and difficult to handle if I keep going on. I don’t know how I will face others. I don’t want anything anymore. I am tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this blog as an outlet of my emotions. At this moment, I know I haven’t made much sense to anyone. But I don’t want it to be read by anyone. This is an outburst. Words are flowing out of me in angst. Hugging my pillow and crying has led me to this. The tears have dried but a disquiet lingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am an Idiot. I am Dust.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a song I listened to a lot in 2010. A Bangla song – আমাকে আমার মত থাকতে দাও . I won’t be translating the title. Until now, I don’t think the lyrics have resonated so much with me. For now, I will find my peace within those words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adios. Until…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; have been asking this question to myself for the past one and a half hours. Particularly, Why Me? Why did I not get selected? A volley of emotions is raging through me right now. I feel dejected, hopeless, worthless, stupid. For the first time in months, I broke down.  I am questioning my feelings, my worth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/08/28/why</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/08/28/why</guid></item><item>
        <title>I've got Mail!</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;n school, we had a topic on letter writing. I always chose formal letters. They were short, scoring. I don’t think I have ever written an informal letter unless compelled to. The prospect of writing to a friend or family and getting it corrected marked by a third person didn’t find any favour in me. These are supposed to be personal, with emotive warmth, soothing. I did not want to get marks by laying bare my personal thoughts to some other person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But once, I wrote a letter. Years back, to my maternal grandfather who very sweetly and kindly replied to me in his impeccable handwriting and gently encouraging me to write more at a time when BSNL landlines already had a presence in our homes. It was perhaps 2004. I was 7 then. And it was the last letter I ever sent until years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I left all (almost) social media platforms at the beginning of this year, I felt a bit left out. While the world around me was constantly engaging for virtual online points, commenting and posting about their life, I was doing nothing, knowing nothing. I forgot birthdays of friends since Facebook wasn’t there to remind me. Always being one day late in my wishes; aided by the WhatsApp statuses and then carefully saving the dates in my calendar. Once, during my occasional periods of thinking and brooding (perks of living alone) I thought people show their affection by changing profile photos and statuses, what happened to birthday cards? My childhood was pretty awesome, I used to get about 3 or 4 cards and display them on the shelves. Times were a bit simpler back then or my desire leads me to believe as such. Very, very few people received one nowadays. And people don’t care or have forgotten the joys of such little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in J, while looking at the letter basket, I found that people have even forgotten their rakhis. Sent by sisters with love from faraway places such as Assam and Dehradun, these bright rakhi envelopes were never opened, never even looked at perhaps. The rakhi and the emotions in them intact, just waiting for the brothers to have a look at them. 7 months later, they are lying in the basket and will perhaps lie there until they are thrown away to make space for new letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Rakhis never opened&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, last year I decided to send a card with a letter. I was a bit apprehensive about how it would be received or whether even it would reach its destination. But what if it reached and just like the rakhis never opened, never even looked at? Because who expects a birthday card, a letter when there are so many ways to wish? I could only wait and hope that the reality turns out to be different than my fears. 2 weeks later, it reached, it was opened, it was loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, I wanted to write more. Part inspired by the love of writing and part inspired by the joy of knowing that the letter was loved. But I had no one to write to. Friends, yes many. But friends who appreciate? Perhaps a few, a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I came across Postcrossing. A site which lets you send picture postcards to anyone in the world and get one in return. I found a place where I could finally write to people and people would write to me. Sending my first five postcards on 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January, I wished them to reach early, very, very early. But postal systems are slow and inefficient. Two of my cards have already expired and perhaps lost on their way to Russia and Finland. There is no tracking, no customer support. They are lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others reached. Everyday in February, while coming back from classes, I made one glance at the letter basket wondering today might be the day. That today came on 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; February all the way from Hawaii travelling for 17 days. It is pretty exciting to get cards from faraway places with exotic stamps and warm, happy messages flooding the letter basket all addressed to me. Finally, I was getting posts, the kind I liked not for any online points but for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I continue with Postcrossing, here are some photos of what I have till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;First postcards sent in January&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Sent from the Golden Temple Post Office in February&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Letterboxes at Patiala Head Post Office&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/i-got-mail-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Postcards mailed on 30th March, 2019&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, people do look up at your mail boxes. Maybe someday, someone will send you some love which you will appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime, earlier this month a classmate looking at a page in my hand saw I wrote Postcrossing and Railfanning as two of my hobbies. He asked, “What are Postcrossing and Railfanning? Never heard about them.” Well, now you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Railfanning, perhaps some other time, some other post…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;n school, we had a topic on letter writing. I always chose formal letters. They were short, scoring. I don’t think I have ever written an informal letter unless compelled to. The prospect of writing to a friend or family and getting it corrected marked by a third person didn’t find any favour in me. These are supposed to be personal, with emotive warmth, soothing. I did not want to get marks by laying bare my personal thoughts to some other person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/31/i-got-mail</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/31/i-got-mail</guid></item><item>
        <title>Songs that defined my 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;his is a late, late 2018 hangover post. I should have been done with it earlier but procrastination got the better of me. I have never been much of music connoisseur. Ever since my schooldays, I have been suggested songs to listen and shared with. That practice hasn’t changed much. People still suggest songs to me and this activity has led to the development of some really cherished friendships. My Aekla Cholo Re credo doesn’t hold much ground here. Whenever people suggest me or share with me songs, I associate a distinct memory of mine with the song. So, whenever I listen to it again, the song reminds me of those memories. And such memories lead the way to more posts such as this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a big thank you to all those who suggested me songs and made my 2018 musically awesome and for lending my brooding self some much needed warmth. I wish all of them a supercalifragilisticexpialidocious 2019!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my 13 songs for 2018. (Click on the name of the song to go to YouTube.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zombie--cranberries&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Ejga4kJUts&quot;&gt;Zombie – Cranberries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first casualty of 2018 brought this song to me in the form of a WhatsApp status from a friend. Before 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January, I didn’t know about Dolores O’Riordan or Cranberries. The hard-hitting lyrics backed by the pummeling, distorted electric guitars and O’Riordian’s lilt reminded me of The Sniper by Liam O’ Flaherty which I read in school and its end. Terrorism is wide spread and it affects people universally whether in India or Ireland. This is a song which I hummed for quite some time on my often-solitary walks from my hostel to college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-moment-in-time--dana-winners-version&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tb6AW00DgTI&quot;&gt;One Moment in Time – Dana Winner’s version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After winning the Chandigarh round of Crucible, I was elated. Sometimes I wondered that I might be dreaming. Our win was real. This song (I prefer this version more than the Whitney Houston one) was shared by my quiz partner who in real terms is a music connoisseur. This song in a way could describe my feelings in the run up to TC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want one moment in time&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When I’m more than I thought I could be&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When all of my dreams are a heartbeat away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;santorini-aria-rain-must-fall--yanni&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6l-lBaP1GzM&quot;&gt;Santorini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=guRM45nE8L0&quot;&gt;Aria&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iq3zo432sAU&quot;&gt;Rain Must Fall&lt;/a&gt; – Yanni&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/songs-of-2018-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, why have I missed this Greek maestro? Discovered Yanni through one of my TC prep nights. Each piece is a magnum opus. The way he incorporates exotic instruments to create music is truly an eclectic fusion of ethnic sounds. His music makes me happy, makes me smile. Personal favourite – Rain Must Fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mamma-mia-here-we-go-again&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLCrKVhZQSHut-2jEtXYbtwzhBqZACp-_C&quot;&gt;Mamma Mia! Here We Go Again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, all the songs of the movie. I was introduced to ABBA in 2016 in my first year of college. Their simple lyrics and happy sounds made them my go to place whenever I was blue. The movie was delight to watch, gives happy vibes. Summer, colourful, musical and Meryl Steep! I am a simple person – I see Meryl Streep, I watch. And till now I have never been disappointed with my choice. Favourites – Thank You for the Music and Andante, Andante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;команда-2018--polina-gagarina-and-egor-creed&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DEkNFao5IdU&quot;&gt;Команда 2018 – Polina Gagarina and Egor Creed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Greatest Celebration on Earth happens every 4 years and brings with a creative outburst of art, music and books. Ever since 2010, I have always been a fan of the non-English versions of the official songs. From Nancy Ajram and Cheb Khaled’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s55Ii15ySHE&quot;&gt;Shajea Helmak&lt;/a&gt; to David Correy and Paty Cantu’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_0GA4ONSEZY&quot;&gt;La Copa de Todos&lt;/a&gt;. Ricky Martin’s Cup of Life from 1998 is still at the top for me though. This year, I was disappointed. None of the songs could capture the zeal and the enthusiasm. Coca Cola was couldn’t live to its expectations. FIFA’s was already a listen-once phenomenon. After some search I came upon Команда 2018 by Polina Gagarina and Egor Creed. It’s completely in Russian, devoid of any recognizable faces but it is infectious! The beats, the rap, the lyrics all fall into place. Throughout the month of June – July ’18 this song remained at the top of my list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-if-god-was-one-of-us--joan-osborne&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Gx1Pv02w3Q&quot;&gt;What If God was One of Us – Joan Osborne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was gifted this song on my birthday by a friend and I have been grateful ever since. This song is my companion during lonely evenings. The music doesn’t distract, the words don’t repulse. Simple, yet so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scarborough-fair--simon-and-garfunkel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-BakWVXHSug&quot;&gt;Scarborough Fair – Simon and Garfunkel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song was casually mentioned by a friend as I was coming out from the hostel mess on a September night. It was the time of my mid sessional yet I was asked to listen to it once. I have been a fan of Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel’s clean sound, folksy lyrics which does not exude a sense of urgency. This is a timeless song. Some how this song escaped my playlist. The brilliance of this piece has been explained by Polyphonic in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lzqau3GOYo8&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube. Combining two different songs into one yet not deviating or overwhelming the listener Scarborough Fair/Canticle is one of my all time great suggested songs so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apocalypse--cigarettes-after-sex&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sElE_BfQ67s&quot;&gt;Apocalypse – Cigarettes After Sex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested just before I was about to take the bus to Delhi for my journey home, this song made my trip much pleasurable. The trance like muted music and its lyrics enchanted me and made my lonesome trip a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You leapt from crumbling bridges watching cityscapes turn to dust&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Filming helicopters crashing in the ocean from way above&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
… &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Oh, when you’re all alone, I will reach for you&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When you’re feeling low, I will be there, too&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diamonds-and-rust--joan-baez&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ST9TZBb9v8&quot;&gt;Diamonds and Rust – Joan Baez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another suggestion from a friend. A retrospective on a long, lost relationship with Bob Dylan by Joan Baez, I spent most of my early November mornings listening to it just to hear this line again and again and again –&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well you burst on the scene&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Already a legend&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The unwashed phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The original vagabond&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tu-kisi-rail-si-guzarti-hai--swanand-kirkire&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zpf8hrbT2d0&quot;&gt;Tu Kisi Rail Si Guzarti Hai – Swanand Kirkire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch a lot of railway videos on YouTube and I think that the site must have seen the word ‘rail’ and put it on my recommendation. Not really a big fan of YouTube’s recommendation algorithm, I have to make an exception for this. This song had me with its opening lines. Personifying the passage of a train over a bridge to young, shy love left me enraptured. Swanand Kirkire’s voice and Varun Grover’s lyrics created magic through this song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tu kisi rail si guzarti hai&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Main kisi pull sa thartharata hoon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gabriels-oboe--ennio-morricone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lAoT2ktM2H0&quot;&gt;Gabriel’s Oboe – Ennio Morricone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/songs-of-2018-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This track from the movie The Mission left me spell-bound. Ennio Morricone is a gift to humanity. Every spaghetti western I have watched had background score by this man. I could not imagine he could also create wonders like this. This is slow but beautiful which needs to be relished. Henrik Chaim Goldschmidt’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WJhax7Jmxs&quot;&gt;version&lt;/a&gt; is a great rendition of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;azaadiyan--amit-trivedi-neuman-pinto-and-amitabh-bhattacharya&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3iCauE_5gMY&quot;&gt;Azaadiyan – Amit Trivedi, Neuman Pinto and Amitabh Bhattacharya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/songs-of-2018-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last week of November amidst the project submissions, quizzes and lab evaluations I found my solace in this. In part due to its lyrics and also due to the film being shot in Jamshedpur with this song being picturized on the Kadma-Sonari Link Road, just metres away from my home. It didn’t bring in me a huge desire to go home but it sure does kindles up some wonderful memories of home and my city. I might perhaps use the last lines of this song for a post years later…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subah Ki Kirno Ko Roke Jo Salaakhein Hai Kahan&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jo Khayalon Pe Pehre Daale&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Woh Aankhein Hai Kahan&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Par Khulne Ki Deri Hai&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Parinde Udh Ke Jhoomenge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;…&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Kahani Khatam Hai&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ya Shuruwaat Hone Ko Hai (Hone Ko Hai)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Subha Nayi Hai Yeh&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ya Phir Raat Hone Ko Hai (Hone Ko Hai)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-prepared--jim-cummings&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zPUe7O3ODHQ&quot;&gt;Be Prepared – Jim Cummings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make – I haven’t watched The Lion King until the November of this year. In all my 21 years of life, I simply gave this film a miss. I missed the bandwagon to watch this when I was young and when I grew up, this felt too cartoonish for me. It was not that this film was completely oblivious to me – the words Simba, Hakuna Matata were known since I was in class 6 or 7. The Circle of Life (which is my first Elton John) was suggested to me in my first year of college. Still, I was not interested in actually watching this. This outlook changed in November. I realized what I missed. One song which will stay with me is Scar’s Be Prepared. What a piece of propaganda music! Rhythmic words, symbolism and a certain grandeur. If I was one of the hyenas, I would have followed Scar just for his choice of words and baritone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, a heartfelt thank you to all those who helped me discover some great music and make my awesome 2018, even more fantastic. Keep suggesting me in 2019 too since I have got a strange feeling of  déjà vu that this year won’t be as happier or exciting as 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All images are screenshots from their video on YouTube. Link given.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;his is a late, late 2018 hangover post. I should have been done with it earlier but procrastination got the better of me. I have never been much of music connoisseur. Ever since my schooldays, I have been suggested songs to listen and shared with. That practice hasn’t changed much. People still suggest songs to me and this activity has led to the development of some really cherished friendships. My Aekla Cholo Re credo doesn’t hold much ground here. Whenever people suggest me or share with me songs, I associate a distinct memory of mine with the song. So, whenever I listen to it again, the song reminds me of those memories. And such memories lead the way to more posts such as this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/02/songs-that-defined-my-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/02/songs-that-defined-my-2018</guid></item><item>
        <title>The Year That Was - 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;ime for some it flies, for others it drags. For me, this year it was mostly the former. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t make any resolutions this year. Left such long ago. I couldn’t keep up with them. Resolutions with an expiry date of barely a few days doesn’t serve any purpose. Rather it was mostly about wandering and coming upon opportunities. The decisions I took were all that made the difference and unlike the previous years, I can end this year with a smile and in high spirits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, here are a few moments from my 2018 when I felt happy, when I felt proud and when I felt grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;january-2018&quot;&gt;January 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tata Crucible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning my first major national level quiz at Chandigarh with RD. There couldn’t have been a better way to start 2018. To those who know me, would very well attribute to the fact that I sulk a bit too often, take in failures too much to my heart. It wouldn’t do well to extrapolate much about it here. Truth be told, I was never confident of winning in Chandigarh. I had enough confidence to make it to the final 8 and perhaps with a bit of luck getting the runners up position. Pressing the buzzer at the very last question and speaking out the correct answer and getting the first position is something I still dream about – How did I do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day I realized two things – I am not that worthless that I assume myself to be and things I wish do come to me, they just take time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;march-2018&quot;&gt;March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Crucible win. Delhi zonals. We qualified for the Nationals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relishing in the comforts of the Tajness at Vivanta by Taj we continued our winning streak. Now, that I type this it really feels surreal. Basking in the pride and happiness, those were some of the best few hours. Even missing my bus to Patiala could not do anything to diminish my spirits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;april-2018&quot;&gt;April 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was now in Bombay for the Finals of Crucible. Although we did not win, to me it would always be the best of times. The time I spent in Bombay visiting, exploring, eating and relaxing to almost missing my flight would be some of the funniest and amazing moments so far. I might be exaggerating but 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April, 2018 needs exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One line from my college’s Twitter account surmises my feelings – We didn’t win the prize but we won hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;august-2018&quot;&gt;August 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some people who might come in briefly into our lives but has a profound effect on us. For me, it would be the one teacher who believed in me when none would and understood me when others wouldn’t. She was like a guardian figure to me. With time, I lost touch until now. Talking to her after 5 years was like a breath of fresh air. I might have never talked to someone for than 3 minutes but with her it was more than an hour. Within that hour I realized what I missed and as always, she believed in a Soham who had stopped believing in himself. Teachers like her make schools and people like me so much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;september-2018&quot;&gt;September 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young, I used to get birthday cards and how excited and thrilled I was to open them and read them. All these years my love for them is there. I now use emails and though in some sense it brings the joy of writing, none can surpass handwritten letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I wrote and sent a letter and a birthday card. Sending it all the way to United Kingdom to a friend who might have appreciated it. I never knew that writing an actual letter could be so tough! What to write when people are already in touch over social media? After 2 failed tries and reading over numerous letters online, I did it. I felt much ecstatic that I wanted to write to everyone I knew. Reality dawned soon and I abandoned my wishful dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month also saw me maintaining a diary. Something which I have wanted to do for long. Writing about my daily life – the good, the bad, the ugly and sometimes nothing at all helped me to speak out about things which I couldn’t with anybody. My secrets, my joys, my tears are all there. My diary sees the best and the worst of me away from the prying eyes of the world and not judging me and this has made me much lighter and happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;october-2018&quot;&gt;October 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living so far from home, I missed one thing dearly – Pujo. The past 2 years I was away from the exuberance of this festival; missing it dearly and yearning to be there with all my heart. But couldn’t. I had almost forgotten what it was during the Pujo and this forgetting made the pain much easier. This year though away from home I saw Pujo albeit in a small way in Chandigarh which bridged a huge chasm in my heart. The fantastic ambiance, the sounds of the &lt;em&gt;dhaks&lt;/em&gt;, Durga thakur and the smell of begunis and fish cutlets evoked in me the sweet memories of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;december-2018&quot;&gt;December 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have taken a revulsion towards social media. I did not have the same urge to be connected as was the urge to be disconnected. The overload of information and the desire of people to depict something which they are not, irritated me, disillusioned me. At the start of this year, I disabled notifications from WhatsApp. I did not login to Facebook at all this year and Twitter had already blocked my account for a few months then reinstated. But now, I do not have the same excitement to login to view what’s up with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I deleted my Instagram account permanently. Twitter and Facebook will follow. This post is the last to be shared over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One good thing came out of all this. Conversations with me are interesting. Not knowing what people are up to through social media, my reactions and my surprises are genuine. I have become a better listener and my life has become much calmer and happier and not interrupted by notifications. I might be missing a lot on my friends but this also showed who really wants to stay in touch with me. I found much more time for reading and blogging than last year.  Being disconnected has an exquisite charm. I discovered it now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;ime for some it flies, for others it drags. For me, this year it was mostly the former. &lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/29/the-year-that-was-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/29/the-year-that-was-2018</guid></item><item>
        <title>Ye Jo Khushi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since my schooldays I have loved October. To me it meant the end of my second terminal examinations, a thing which I used to do better than I supposedly do now in college. I wasn’t really that afraid of the papers – I enjoyed it. The weather was better, afternoons less hot and I could laze around the house reading, watching TV or just day dreaming, counting days left until Pujo and talking to myself while others slept. There was not much to do. I used to look forward to the Pujo edition of Graphiti which used to come with The Telegraph. Stories of old, doodles by Biplab Deb and amusing myself with the repartee of the columnists. Derek still used to maintain his quizzing column with occasional questions from his father’s DI Quiz. Pujo for Bengalis is not only restricted to devotion – it’s an amalgamation of spending days shopping when even the most serious and easily irritable Baba left his newspaper or sports to lend his decision (and open his wallet) on the quality and showed his bargaining prowess (which until then was a quality only accorded to the missus of the house), of being carefree and given the freedom to stay until 8 at night, of being given an allowance for Pujo, of binge eating on golgappas, ice creams, chats, chowmein and not being scolded for it. To some it also meant trying to find that someone special in the crowds of the pandal and spending hours dreaming. It was when the word crush just meant a physical activity and infatuation was yet to come into my vocabulary. The disappointment was never to last long – there were many pandals, many hopes, many stories yet to be written. Bengalis have humanized their favourite deity – goddess Durga and is worshipped as much as demon-slayer, bringer of justice as a daughter returning to her home, Earth with her children, their mama bari. To me it also represented a time when social networks were yet to pervade our lives and special Pujo ads meant for a specific demographic didn’t attract FIRs as it does now. So much for being connected!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was home. Now, I am in college and since 2016, I have missed Pujo. The first year was difficult. My roommates had left, the campus was almost empty and the mess stopped serving eggs because of Navratri (a tradition which even now in 2018 I have not been able to adapt to – Pujo and no non-veg? Atrocious! Revolting!). I was pretty much alone and sad. Used to spend my days watching Star Ananda in the evenings and listening to Bangla songs to get over my lonely life. It was not homesickness, it still isn’t. The environment was what I missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second year too went by. Not too much sad now. Getting used to it. Continued to pester (and perhaps annoy) my friends to send me photos and videos from wherever they are. I have kept up with this tradition ever since. Sitting in my room, I saw pujos of Jamshedpur, Bombay and Delhi NCR. I cannot be thankful to them enough. Every day after coming back from my classes, those notifications of photos and videos would make my day. On doshomi, I took a photo of mine in a red kurta and uploaded on Instagram and Facebook. Shouldn’t have. I still used to be active on those last year. The photo still exists as my own contact image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third Year. To be honest, I didn’t really care enough for Pujo. My memory of it has faded and with it my longing. Still I was looking forward for October. Elixir was at the end of the month, the nights were becoming chilly, days were shorter, I could snug in comfortably in my welcoming bed and read or watch something – a myriad of possibilities. Pujo was not even on my mind. Instead I was looing forward for the Friday when it would be Doshomi. Extended weekend and less people on campus. Perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year was different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous years, I had searched for Pujos in Patiala. Nada. Not even a single hit on Google. This time I had a fellow Bong friend who too was missing Pujos this time (he would have been in Bombay otherwise). It was his first time and the hope of attending a Pujo in his eyes were evident. I was unfazed. He was not. After much asking and talking he found out two Pujos happen in Patiala – one in Qila Chowk and the other in Patiala Cantonment (I knew about this one but was apprehensive of entering a security establishment in Punjab giving Pujo as the reason).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;saptami---16th-october&quot;&gt;Saptami - 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baba had just flushed in some money into my account (Pujo allowance) and on Saptami, we went to Qila Chowk, in the old quarters of Patiala. Navigating through the narrow streets with its jewelry, Punjabi jutti, clothes, karyana stores and having a rosogollas at the old Jaggi near AC Market, we found it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place used to be the entrance of the fort of the erstwhile royal family of Patiala – Qila Mubarak (Fort Congratulations). It was dark. But the damage to the 18th century fortress was evident – in front of the square or Chowk was a temple, the rest of it covered with shops on four sides, their signage covering the vast arched entrance to the fort. The people were unaware. Or perhaps were so used to their heritage in their daily lives that preservation never came to their mind. The left side of the Chowk was occupied by street food stalls of chat, champ and surprisingly dosa. They weren’t too crowded. The plastic chairs were empty and the owners were eager for business. The people passed them by and the stoves were yet to be lighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Qila Chowk, Patiala&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The red brick structure was built in 1763 in Sikh architectural style by the founder of the Patiala dynasty, Baba Ala Singh. For centuries it was the seat of power and the first fort of the city. Now, it sits at the intersection of three major commercial spines – Gur Mandi, Bajaja Bazaar and Shah Nashin Bazaar. I entered the gate of the fort and looked up to see a fine circular stucco decoration half of which had disintegrated. Further on, it was dark, empty. Outside the entrance there was a sign – Qila Mubarak. Patiala Heritage. The sign had faded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Gateway to Qila Mubarak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it wasn’t for the Pujo, I wouldn’t have visited. In all my life I have never seen such a quiet Durga Pujo. Organized the local Bengalis who in an earlier time had migrated to work here as jewelry craftsmen and other small-time jobs, the absence of a Dhaki was a solemn affair. Perhaps their years of living in Punjab and learning the ways of the locals or even the monetary affair made the exclusion of the Dhaki a bit more plausible. Seeing thakur after 3 years was overwhelming for me. I was struck by her unwavering gaze, that barely noticeable smile and her towering yet benevolent figure. Durga is a mother goddess, her protective form willing to unleash against the wrong. Joined my palms, bowed before her and prayed. I must have stood transfixed for quite a few minutes before my friend nudged me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Qila Chowk Durga Pujo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;asthami--17th-october&quot;&gt;Asthami – 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Youth Welfare Club of Thapar organizes a Jagran on Asthami evening and continues till late at night. COS is lighted up, girls have got late permi, and the for boys a few more hours with the opposite sex. I have given this event a miss since 2016 since I could not relate to it. I couldn’t understand the bhajans or why the crowd went berserk. This time I decided to go (on persuasion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the entrance of OAT, there was a big block of ice, around 2 feet tall rectangular block. There were leaves stuck on it. At the first I couldn’t fathom what could it be. The Bengali in me for whom Pujo is a synonym for food thought it was for the ice lolly or chuskis. Forgive me! I couldn’t have been more wrong. It was a shivling for the God Shiva. Inside I was exposed to different culture. The stage had a huge cutout of Shiva decorated with garlands and detachable scenes of mountains. Just below it was the figurine of Maa Parvati, another form of Maa Durga in a red saree, sitting over her consort – the lion and having the same benign stare at the students who had gathered there to perhaps just enjoy the environment and the night. She is not judging. She knows. One major difference I noticed here was the ghumta or headscarf was over her head. Such a sight was a bit unsettling for me. For years, the depictions of Durga I had seen was of a normal woman – never one with a headscarf, trying to go low. She came to her people, she was one with them. There was grace. In all my years, I had looked at Durga Pujo from a Bengali perspective, this time it was Durga Puja and the North Indian version though vastly different from mine had its own takers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Jagrata at Thapar University&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jagran would go on till 4 in the morning. I wasn’t very enthusiastic about it to attend till that late. From 10:30 at night, the guards and the people made an announcement that girls will only be allowed to leave with the guards to their hostel. Such an escorted service would be provided at every 90 minutes. I quickly made an exit. Thapar is very serious about not letting the two sexes leave together. If I had delayed then I could only go after the girls had left. Outside I stood for a few minutes – observing and humouring myself with what I was seeing. The machismo, the bravado and the sense of pride of the boys and the guards who were lining up the girls according to their hostels were evident as if they were escorting criminals to their cells after their day out. It sickened me. When I first came to Thapar, the campus was still less lighted – the Haveli, the Dispensary ground were not covered with the harsh gaze of lights. The reason given was safety. Today, the 300-meter stretch was deemed unsafe in spite of the lights and the students moving about that an escort was deemed necessary for the girls. They were celebrating a female goddess inside, singing songs, clapping and devouring her prasad with utmost piety. Outside, a different story was told which border which was edged on by the sycophancy of the few. The girls were led back to their hostels, with their high walls and barbed wires. Walled Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;navami--18th-october&quot;&gt;Navami – 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we could not enter the Patiala Cantonment without passes and had professors who weren’t too helpful to us in this regard, we decided to go to Chandigarh. That city has around 3 or 4 Durga Pujos and we hoped to see at least some of them if not all. Chandigarh was an unfamiliar place – none of us had been there for much time. We made liberal use of Google Maps to decide our itinerary. Chandigarh is a little more than an hour’s journey from Patiala. The bus will pass through small villages with evocative names like Kauli, Kheri Gandhian, Dharreri Jattan. Everywhere where the eyes went, the landscape was covered in a patchwork of lemon yellow and green fields, sometimes broken only by the transmission poles which criss crossed the horizon with its lines. Somewhere the walls of the houses which happened to be near the National Highway 7 were painted with advertisements of firms to help clear IELTS, TOEFL and getting the much-desired thing in Punjab – a visa for Canada, Australia and UK in that order. Leaving Patiala, one comes across the industrial plant of Federal Moghul which manufactures power trains. From the window, the compound stretched on – the guest house with its well-maintained lawns, the administrative building the front of which has a water fountain working even in the heat of the plains of Northern India. The chimneys, the tin sheds and almost dilapidated sheds for vehicle parking. For a moment, as I watched on I was reminded of my city albeit in a miniature scale – the factory around which an entire town has grown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandigarh has more in common with Jamshedpur than any city I have been to. Jamshedpur was the first industrial planned city in India and Chandigarh which was built about half a decade later shares many aspects – leafy trees covering the roads, the traffic islands, the sign boards of directions to different sectors, each roundabout having its own automatic traffic lights. There are bushes and trees even on the dividers. Greener and cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pujo was what I experienced here after a drought of 3 years. Chandigarh Kalibari was good but I couldn’t come to like it as much as it was advertised. There was a mela outside – food stalls, crafts stall, a sitting vendor with roasted peanuts, a young tired looking boy with balloons in his hand for sale. An old man with a long wooden pole from where flutes and other toys jutted out. Yes, it was a Pujo Mela. But somewhere the feeling of it was missing. Perhaps I had expected too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Chandigarh Kalibari Durga Pujo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banga Bhavan at Sector 35C was in my opinion a much better ambience. Small and homely. Not much of a mela rather a mela of food stalls were inside the small premises. Calcutta style egg rolls, fish cutlets, ghugni, fish fry, chicken kebabs and biryani – defying the Navratri this was a mini Bengal in the heart of Chandigarh. The results of a drawing competition for children were pinned against the wall. The theme was Environment or Durga Pujo. A stage was set up for some culturals to be held later on, a man with table full of books of Mario Puzo, Vivekananda, Tagore, Franz Kafka, Dan Brown sat just outside the Pujo mandap. It is difficult to find a Bengali without a taste for such finer things. Banga Bhavan encapsulated all these within their small premises for these few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Dhaki at Banga Bhavan Durga Pujo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back on the last bus home – the 9:45 to Patiala. &lt;em&gt;Yes, home&lt;/em&gt; my friend said. No matter how much we chide or scoff at this small town, living here made it feel like home with the knowledge that we are back again at familiar sights and smell. There is a certain small town charm to this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ye-jo-khushi-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; 
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Tagore, Kafka, Premchand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I received Pujo photos from Jamshedpur, Durgapur, Chittaranjan Park Delhi and even Manchester, United Kingdom. A veritable assortment of images and memories now abound in my consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of this post Ye Jo Khushi is loose Bengali translation of ই জে উল্লাস which accompanied my status on Navami. I received quite a few curious messages regarding this. So, here, this post is what it stands for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one regret which I have then it would be my inability to take better photos in order to merely try to bring out the vibrancy of this festival. Perhaps next time…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since my schooldays I have loved October. To me it meant the end of my second terminal examinations, a thing which I used to do better than I supposedly do now in college. I wasn’t really that afraid of the papers – I enjoyed it. The weather was better, afternoons less hot and I could laze around the house reading, watching TV or just day dreaming, counting days left until Pujo and talking to myself while others slept. There was not much to do. I used to look forward to the Pujo edition of Graphiti which used to come with The Telegraph. Stories of old, doodles by Biplab Deb and amusing myself with the repartee of the columnists. Derek still used to maintain his quizzing column with occasional questions from his father’s DI Quiz. Pujo for Bengalis is not only restricted to devotion – it’s an amalgamation of spending days shopping when even the most serious and easily irritable Baba left his newspaper or sports to lend his decision (and open his wallet) on the quality and showed his bargaining prowess (which until then was a quality only accorded to the missus of the house), of being carefree and given the freedom to stay until 8 at night, of being given an allowance for Pujo, of binge eating on golgappas, ice creams, chats, chowmein and not being scolded for it. To some it also meant trying to find that someone special in the crowds of the pandal and spending hours dreaming. It was when the word crush just meant a physical activity and infatuation was yet to come into my vocabulary. The disappointment was never to last long – there were many pandals, many hopes, many stories yet to be written. Bengalis have humanized their favourite deity – goddess Durga and is worshipped as much as demon-slayer, bringer of justice as a daughter returning to her home, Earth with her children, their mama bari. To me it also represented a time when social networks were yet to pervade our lives and special Pujo ads meant for a specific demographic didn’t attract FIRs as it does now. So much for being connected!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/22/ye-jo-khushi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/22/ye-jo-khushi</guid></item><item>
        <title>Example Post Formatting</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heading-1&quot;&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-2&quot;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heading-3&quot;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heading-4&quot;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading-5&quot;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading-6&quot;&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Donec sed odio dui. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unordered-list&quot;&gt;Unordered List&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longer List Item
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested List Item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ordered-list&quot;&gt;Ordered List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Longer List Item
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nested OL Item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;definition-list&quot;&gt;Definition List&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Coffee&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Black hot drink&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Milk&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;White cold drink&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Donec sed odio dui. Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/15/example-post-formatting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/15/example-post-formatting</guid></item><item>
        <title>Featured Image</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/14/featured-image</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2014/12/14/featured-image</guid></item></channel>
</rss>
